Steven A. Babcock

2250 Kenneth Crescent Burlington, ON, L7L 6T4 Phone: 416-456-0301

E-mail: Steven.A.Babcock@gmail.com

Objectives

My ideal role would be as an Application Consultant / Sales Engineer where I can utilize my diverse skill set in the area of Business Systems. I have worked with various workforce systems including Human Resources, Canadian Payroll, Complex Staff Scheduling & Time & Attendance.

I have worked with and sold both on-premise solutions as well as SAAS offerings. I am qualified to discuss the advantages and disadvantages (both real and perceived) of each offering and am well versed in ROI discussions and business case creation.

I have over 13 years of experience in the EIM field, with a wide range of expertise in workforce solutions.

Experience

Solutions Consultant (March 2011 – Present) QHR Software (Kelowna BC, Toronto ON)

- Prepare detailed responses to RFPs
- Demonstrate Products through effective on site presentations and online demonstrations.
- Participate is discovery sessions with existing clients and prospects
- Improve and optimize the sales process
- Develop business cases including ROI documentation
- Perform customer and prospect based webinars
- Consult with Product Management and Development on various product initiatives

Enterprise Sales Executive (November 2005 – March 2011) HR Technologies Inc. (Toronto, ON)

- Selling HR, Payroll and Time & Attendance Solutions to a Wide Range of Companies
- Completion of RFP's and RFI's
- Performing Detailed Discoveries, both Funded and Unfunded
- Performing System Demonstrations
- Performing Technical Discoveries relating to our various solutions and supported software platforms

Application Specialist (July 2002 – November 2005) HR Technologies Inc. (Toronto, ON)

- Performed Discoveries and Demonstrations on Various Applications
- Assisted the Sales Team Throughout the Sales Process
- Standardized Discovery and Demonstration Processes

Software Quality Analyst (February 2000 – July 2002) HR Technologies Inc. (Toronto, ON)

- Created Comprehensive Regression Testing Procedures
- Created Automated Test Scripts using QA Run and Test Partner

Additional Duties (2000 - 2010)

- Network Administration Including Complete Implementation of Network Services
- SQL Server Programming (Triggers, Stored Procedures) for Various Systems
- Implementation of Salesforce.com
- Standardization of all Sales Processes

Technical Skills

Proficient in the Installation, Use and Maintenance of the Following Systems

- Microsoft SQL Server 2000/2005/2008/2012
- Microsoft Windows Server 2000/2003/2008
- Microsoft IIS 5.0/6.0/7.0
- Windows 2000+
- Passionate evangelist for all iOS devices and Apple Product Line
- Office 2000+

Capable in the Following Programming Languages

- Microsoft VB 6.0
- VB.Net
- SQL Server
- Microsoft VBA
- Force.com
- X-Code

Education

Meadowvale Secondary School - 1994-1999

Graduation in 1999

Sheridan College - 2002-2004

MCSE+I Prep Courses, Human Resources Management